/*jshint esversion: 6 */

// questions and answers array for quizData
let quizData = [{
        question: "Which is the first planet in the solar system from the sun?",
        answers: {
            a: "Venus",
            b: "Saturn",
            c: "Jupiter",
            d: "Mercury"
        },
        correctAnswer: "Mercury"
    },
    {
        question: "We can't see the surface of Venus from space in visible light. Why?",
        answers: {
            a: "It doesn't have a surface",
            b: "None of these",
            c: "The light from the sun reflects directly on the surface",
            d: "Venus is covered with a thick layer of clouds"
        },
        correctAnswer: "Venus is covered with a thick layer of clouds"
    },
    {
        question: "The second largest moon in our solar system is a natural satellite of Saturn. What is its name?",
        answers: {
            a: "Titan ",
            b: "Europa",
            c: "Rhea",
            d: "Mimas"
        },
        correctAnswer: "Titan "
    },
    {
        question: "Between which two planets is the asteroid belt found?",
        answers: {
            a: "Mars and Jupiter ",
            b: "Neptune and Pluto",
            c: "Saturn and Uranus",
            d: "All of these"
        },
        correctAnswer: "Mars and Jupiter "
    },
    {
        question: "Neptune was the first planet to be found by which method?",
        answers: {
            a: "Telescope ",
            b: "All of these",
            c: "The naked eye",
            d: "Mathematical prediction"
        },
        correctAnswer: "Mathematical prediction"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of these chemical can you find the most of, in the sun?",
        answers: {
            a: "Carbon ",
            b: "Hydrogen",
            c: "Oxygen",
            d: "Nitrogen"
        },
        correctAnswer: "Hydrogen"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the diameter of the sun?",
        answers: {
            a: "About 1.4 million kilometres",
            b: "About 2.3 million kilometres",
            c: "About 1.2 million kilometres",
            d: "About 3.2 million kilometres"
        },
        correctAnswer: "About 1.4 million kilometres"
    },
    {
        question: "Which is the world’s largest light detecting telescope?",
        answers: {
            a: "Chantra X-ray telescope",
            b: "Hubble telescope",
            c: "The Twin Keck telescopes",
            d: "Mercury Telescope",
        },
        correctAnswer: "The Twin Keck telescopes"
    },
    {

        question: "How long did it take the Cassini-Huygens spacecraft to reach Saturn?",
        answers: {
            a: "Almost seven years",
            b: "Less than six year",
            c: "More than seven years",
            d: "Six months"
        },
        correctAnswer: "Almost seven years"
    },
    {
        question: "Which was the first living creature to be sent to space?",
        answers: {

            a: "Laika the dog",
            b: "Yuri Gagarin",
            c: "A monkey",
            d: "Your pet hamster"
        },
        correctAnswer: "Laika the dog"
    },
    {
        question: "Who was the first woman to travel to space?",
        answers: {
            a: "Alexei Leonov",
            b: "Valentina Tereshkova",
            c: "Kalpana Chawla",
            d: "Ana Putin"
        },
        correctAnswer: "Kalpana Chawla"
    },
    {
        question: "Which soviet astronaut performed the first ever spacewalk?",
        answers: {
            a: "Yuri Gagarin",
            b: "Alexei Leonov",
            c: "Edward White",
            d: "Alexi Rosonovski"
        },
        correctAnswer: "Alexei Leonov"
    },
    {
        question: "Who was the first person in space?",
        answers: {
            a: "Neil Armstrong",
            b: "Vlad Yeltsin",
            c: "Kalpana Chawla",
            d: "Yuri Gagarin"
        },
        correctAnswer: "Yuri Gagarin"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of these is a satellite of Pluto?",
        answers: {
            a: "Lo",
            b: "Charon",
            c: "Ariel",
            d: "Titiana"
        },
        correctAnswer: "Charon"
    },
    {
        question: "How far is the Proxima Centauri star from earth?",
        answers: {
            a: "50 billion kilometres",
            b: "More than 40 trillion kilometres",
            c: "40 million kilometres",
            d: "Almost 40 trillion kilometres"
        },
        correctAnswer: "Almost 40 trillion kilometres"
    },
    {

        question: "The nearest star to earth, after the sun, is",
        answers: {
            a: "Proxima Centauri",
            b: "Barnard’s star",
            c: "Gliese 581",
            d: "Kepler"
        },
        correctAnswer: "Proxima Centauri"
    },
    {
        question: "When you are on Mars, the sunset looks like which colour?",
        answers: {
            a: "Orange",
            b: "Purple",
            c: "Red",
            d: "Blue"
        },
        correctAnswer: "Blue"
    }
];

export default quizData;